JITAN GUPTA

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

Creative .NET Developer with almost 8 years of strong experience in both front-end development and back-end development areas with a willingness to learn and master any technology as long as the work is exciting. GOF Design Pattern & OOP practitioner.

Key Skills

Frontend: Angular, TypeScript, HTML

Server: .NET Core, C#. MVC, Web API, Entity Framework Core, SQL Server

System Design: Micro-service & Monolithic Architecture, SOLID Principles, Design Patterns

DevOps: GitHub, Kibana, Jenkins, Jira, Confluence

Additionally: Team Leading, Code Review and Documentation.

Work History

Lead Engineer (Full-Stack)

12/2021 - Present

Kaplan India Pvt. Ltd.

- Leading the team for migrating the legacy app to the new .NET Core app.
- Adding new features & managing production releases for an internal app.
- Researching and integrating third-party tools into the application.
- Writing complex business logic, doing code reviews, guiding team members and documenting my findings.

Senior Software Engineer (Full-Stack)

02/2019 - 12/2021

NEC Software Solutions

- Working in sprints to add new features to the platform, following 'Test-Driven Development' and 'Code Review Policy' to ensure code quality
- Doing POCs sometimes and presenting to the Product manager before it gets implemented to the platform.

Software Engineer (Full-Stack)

09/2016-02/2019

NeoSoft Technology (Client – Mahindra Finance)

- Ideated, designed, developed and shipped client-facing and supporting applications for Fixed Deposit
- Migrated internal project into .NET Core and managed a team of 3 people while migration.

Web Developer (Full-Stack)

12/2015-09/2016

Artcarro Art Services Pvt. Ltd.

- Doing market research and brainstorming for the features
- Ideated, designed, developed and shipped the client and admin portal for Artcarro.

Achievements & Awards

- Increased the revenue by **150%** by creating a **chrome extension aggregator** to add more data to the platform.
- Managing complete **SDLC** and a **team of 3 developers** at JugaadHai.
- Received "Feather in the cap" award for Migrating the application using Bootstrap 3 to bootstrap 4.5 at NEC Software Solutions
- Trained 3 new graduates and led them while migrating a legacy application at MahindraFinance

Jitan Gupta, Email: hi@jitangupta.com

Jitan Gupta, Email: hi@jitangupta.com

Work History

JugaadHai

JugaadHai is an online platform that provides tricks and deals to save money while transactingonline.

Tech-Stack: **C#, SQL, .NET Core, Angular, GitHub, Digital Ocean, Jira** Responsibility:

- Created the architecture of JugaadHai by following best practices, design patterns and SOLID design principles while keeping in mind, scalability, maintainability and robustness
- Brainstorming & finalizing new features, creating sprints & assigning them to team members
- Doing code reviews & maintaining the code quality and standards.

Kaplan North America (KNA) Admin Dashboard

KNA Admin Dashboard is an MVC application used as an internal tool to manage and configure public-facing applications.

Tech Stack: .Net Core, C#, SQL, EF, Dapper, Micro Service Architecture, xUnit, jQuery, Bootstrap
Team Size: 8

Electronic Document & Record Management System (EDRM)

EDRM is a document management solution used by the UK Government to manage its citizen'sdocuments. (NEC Project, other information is present in the experience section.)

Tech Stack: .NET Framework, C#, SQL, MVC, .Net Core, Azure DevOps, EF, Knockout JS, jQuery

Team Size: 28

Fixed Deposit (FD)

FD is an investment platform where people can invest money in fixed deposit services provided by Mahindra Finance.

Tech Stack: .NET Framework, C#, MVC, SQL, jQuery, BootstrapTeam Size: 5 Responsibility:

- Provided support for existing FD portal
- Created a separate module to sell FD in a better way (Fixed Deposit Quick Buy)
- Created a customer support application to help customers in buying the FDs, used by callcenter people

We Love Startups (startup)

We Love Startups is a community for entrepreneurs, startup founders, developers, designers, marketers, photographers, and bloggers.

Role: Front-end developer & Community Coordinator

Tech Stack: MEAN StackResponsibility:

- Developed the community application to showcase the event and attendee registration
- Managing the people in the event.

There are a lot more projects I have worked on which haven't been included here...

Education

Bachelor of Science – Information Technology

Mumbai University (2012 – 2015)

Diploma in .NET Programming

Central Board of IT & Vocation Training (2014)